忘了问了 当时疼吗
Oh, I forgot to ask- Did it hurt?
什么疼吗
What hurt?
你从天堂坠落凡间 接触地面的那一刻
When you fell from heaven and landed on earth.
我才没从天堂...
I didn't fall from- Ah.
你是说我像个天使
Because I'm an angel.
你嘴巴怎么这么甜
Why are you so sweet?
或许只是因为我心情太好吧
Maybe just 'cause I'm so damn happy.
今天是杰的生日
Today's Ja y's birthday,
所以我要带他去夏威夷呆上一整个星期
so I'm taking him to Hawaii for a whole week.
茂伊岛的豪华套房 两人的私密空间
Big suite in Maui. Just the two of us.
把曼尼拴在后院 留一大碗狗食给他
Got Manny tied up in the backyard. Big bowl of kibble.
开个玩笑 交给克莱尔和菲尔了
I'm kidding. He's staying with Claire and Phil.
此次旅行他完全不知情
This whole thing was a big surprise.
我一手包办 订机票 订酒店
I did it all myself- the flight, the hotels.
虽说花了我不少钱 不过绝对值
Cost me a fortune, but it was worth it.
尽管说了千万遍 不过还是要再说一遍
In case I forget to say it a few hundred times this week,
谢谢你
thank you.
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
这 这是搞什么
Wh- What the heck?
-惊喜 爸爸 -全家都会跟我们一起去
- Surprise, Dad. - The whole family's coming with us!
-真的吗 -没错
- They are? - Uh-huh.
没错 米奇尔 卡梅隆和莉莉也来
Yes, and Mitch and Cameron and Lily too.
是啊 菲尔正在托运行李呢
Yeah, and Phil- he's just checking the bags. Wow!
可真是...
That's, uh- Wow.
都是歌洛莉亚的主意
It was all Gloria's idea.
她把我们机票什么的都包了
She bought all of our tickets and everything.
-是吗 所有人的 -没错
- Really? Everyone's? - Yeah.
你过生日嘛 该花就得花
It's your birthday. I didn't spare any expense.
天啊 谢谢你了 亲爱的
Oh, gee! Thank you, honey.
那他们 都跟我们一起坐头等舱吗
Are they, uh, all gonna be up with us in first class?
傻啊老公 经济舱啦 你当我是摇钱树啊
Ay, no, silly. Coach. You think I'm made of money?
当然不是
Of course not.
我们要吃夏威夷野猪宴
We're gonna go to a luau,
跟迈阿密海豚一起游泳
swim with the Miami Dolphins,
坐着那啥啥环游
take a tour in one of those, the-
-直升飞机 -没错
- Helicopter. Helicopter. - Mm-hmm. Yes!
我不爱参加活动
I don't like activities.
我就想跟歌洛莉亚到处转转
I wanted to hang out with Gloria
读一读罗伯特·勒德拉姆的小说
and read my Robert Ludlum novels.
我这电子书里存了整整八本
I got eight of 'em loaded up on my book reader thing here.
别误会 我爱我的家人
I mean, I love my family.
共进晚餐啦 吃吃烧烤啦都不错
I love 'em at dinners, I love 'em at barbecues,
但干嘛非要到夏威夷去啊
but do I have to love 'em in Hawaii?
谢了 达里尔
Thanks, Daryl.
我知道自己行李[心理]负担不少
I know I got a lot of baggage,
不过别担心 我在看心理医生
but don't worry, I'm seeing a therapist.
开个玩笑 我没事
Just kidding. I'm fine.
达里尔 我认识这帮人
Daryl, I know these guys.
帽子能借我演个戏吗 肯定会很搞笑
Can I borrow your hat? This will be hilarious.
-不行 -好吧
- No. - Okay.
你好啊 菲尔姑父
Aloha, Uncle Phil!
要去旅行了激动吗
You guys excited about the trip?
激动死了 你知道吗 这是我的第一次
Oh, we're so excited. You know, this is my first time.
-真的吗 -是啊 我知道很不可思议
- Really? Yeah, I know it's surprising.
大家总说我弥漫着"夏威夷"的气息
People always say I scream "Hawaii."
谁说的
Who says that?
-一些人 -哪些人
- People. - What people?
说了你也不认识
You don't know them.
-嘿 莉莉 嗨 -噢不
- Hey, Lily! Hi. - Oh, no! Oh, n-
我忘带钱包了
I forgot my wallet.
没事 我有现金
Oh, that's all right. I have cash.
不是 我没带身份证不能登机
No, no. I can't get on the plane without my I.D.
-多亏了你 小卡 -怎么能赖我
- Thanks a lot, Cam. - How is this my fault?
因为早上你要是按我说的做了
Because if you had done what I asked you to do this morning,
我就不会忙得团团转
then I wouldn't have been overwhelmed
也不会把钱包落家里了
and I would have remembered my wallet.
好了 还得把莉莉的玩具打包
All right. We still need to pack Lily's toys,
打印登机牌
print the boarding passes.
暂停报纸的递送
Oh, stop the newspaper.
等等 你在做什么 我刚打包好的
Wait. What are you doing? I just packed those.
她穿这身衣裳太可爱了
She just looks so cute in this outfit.
我想要她以最佳状态去见贾斯珀
I want her looking her best for Jasper.
你刚说的我一句听不懂
Nothing you just said made any sense to me.
贾斯珀和他妈妈要来跟莉莉玩
Jasper and his mother are coming over for a playdate.
我们几周前定好的
We scheduled it weeks ago.
-我们要去机场了 -还有一小时呢
- We're about to leave for the airport. - Not for an hour.
贾斯珀只有这时候有空
And this is the only time Jasper could do it.
贾斯珀是有多忙啊
How full is Jasper's calendar?
此乃妙计 只要跟贾斯珀套上近乎
This is a coup. When you get in with Jasper,
万事都轻松
doors open.
他可是快乐时光幼儿园里的大明星
He's a legacy at Happy Time Preschool.
我们连10个月大小孩的马屁都要拍吗
We're kissing up to a 10-month-old?
我只是希望留个好印象嘛
I just want him to like us.
好了 他们来了
Okay, that's them.
进来坐会儿就得了
But just in and out.
还有一堆事要忙活呢
We still have a million things to do.
能放松点吗 你总爱瞎操心 没事的
Would you relax? You always worry. It always gets done.
对了 记住 我们是循道宗信徒
Oh, and we're Methodists, so-
骗谁呢我 这肯定是赶不上飞机了
Uh, who am I kidding? I'm not making this flight.
我开车送你回去
Uh-uh. I can get you home
然后飞机起飞前赶回来 走吧
and back before the plane takes off. Let's go.
达里尔 想个法子让飞机晚点起飞
Daryl- See if you can stall the plane.
这个...我待会儿再付给你
That's- I will get to you later.
我真觉得 真觉得肯定赶不上
I really- I really don't think there's enough time.
去吧 在登机口见 去吧
Go. I'll meet you at the gate. Go.
-你不会丢我一人自己去玩吧 -这个
- But you won't get on the plane without me, right? - Oh. Well-
真的假的 你打算自己去吗 小卡
Seriously? You were gonna get on the plane? Cam!
你就去吧
Just go!
不行 后面也得关上
Nope. Gotta get that one.
不行 我关不上
Okay. I can't-
-噢 真是慢得要死 -赶紧开
- Oh! That's as fast as she goes. - Just drive.
-赶紧开 -行李交给我吧
- Just drive. - I'll get the luggage!
快瞧瞧那帅哥
Hey, check out that cute guy.
他跟你可不是一路人 他在读书呢
He's out of your league. He's reading a book.
我知道
I know.
-就是今天 奔赴茂伊 -看见菲尔没
- Here today, gone to Maui! - Hey. You seen Phil?
-他载米奇尔回家去拿钱包了 -什么
- Oh, he drove Mitchell back to get his wallet. - What?
是啊 他说一定能及时赶回来
Yeah. He said he's gonna make it back in time,
要我看悬啊
but I think it's gonna be close.
他就把我扔这儿了
So he left me here.
海莉还没起来 卢克人也不知道哪儿去了
Haley is still asleep, and I have no idea where Luke is.
你到底准备好了没啊
And are you even ready?
我的包都放在客厅了 一切都会没事的啦
My bag's in the living room. Everything's gonna be okay.
好吧 抱歉 我有点小紧张
Okay. Fine. I'm sorry. I'm a little tense.
那你还喝咖啡
Coffee'll help that.
你说得对
You're right.
我们不是聊过了嘛 航空旅行非常安全
We've been over this. Air travel is incredibly safe.
我知道 我知道的 不过话说回来
I know. I know. But at the end of the day,
它就是天空中的一座建筑
it is still a building on its side
横着被扔过来扔过去呗
being thrown from one place to another.
-有电影看 -顶屁用
- With a movie. - Not helping.
要不要来点什么药 帮助你缓缓神
You wanna take something, maybe calm your nerves?
不行 孩子们还指着我呢 我要清醒
No. No. I wanna be alert if the kids need me.
好伟大的母亲 有时我都希望你能是我母亲
What a mom. Sometimes I wish you were my mom.
天啊 菲尔 我已经有点想吐了
Oh, God, Phil. I'm already feeling a little queasy.
我讨厌这种感觉 特讨厌
I hate this feeling. I hate it.
越是快上飞机这感觉就会越强烈
And it's just gonna get worse and worse until the flight.
没事的啦
It's gonna be fine.
有菲尔大叔在呢
Uncle Phil's here.
好样的 老弟 第一个准备好的
Great job, buddy! First one ready.
海莉 艾丽克斯 要走了
Haley and Alex, let's go!
上帝保佑
Bless you.
-来了 -好的快跟上 姑娘们
- Coming. - All right. Come on, girls.
练兵千日 用兵一时啊
Okay. This is why we practice.
-就来了 就来了 -十五秒的时间
- Come on through. Come through. - Fifteen seconds.
-准备好了吗 -准备好了
- Are we ready? - I think so.
动起来吧
It's go time.
直奔小车 欲速则不达 慢慢来
Straight to the car. Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast.
走 走 走 欲速则不达 慢慢来
Go, go, go, go, go. Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast.
-太棒了 -很好 快走 快走
- Very nice! -Alright. Let's go. Let's go.
-好像还多余几秒呢 -不多
- I think we got an extra couple of seconds. - No,
-没有 -老爸 赶紧的
- we don't. - Dad, come on!
真想这么抱你一整天
I will never get tired of this.
我也是
Me neither.
老妈知道怎么样才最酷吗
You know what would be cool, Mum?
怎么样
What's that?
就是飞机直插入暴风雨
If the plane flew into a storm
然后像《迷失》里那样坠毁在一座岛上
and crash-landed onto an island like in Lost.
哪里不对劲吗 小卡
Something wrong there, Cam?
新买的登山鞋磨得我脚生疼啊
Well, I'm just breaking in a new pair of hiking shoes.
一向如此 我们家的男人脚踝都比较粗壮
This always happens. All the men in my family have wide ankles.
我有个叔叔只能穿喇叭裤 对天发誓
I have an uncle that can only wear bell bottoms. Hand to God.
我相信你
I wasn't doubtin' ya.
只是纳闷儿你为什么要穿个登山鞋
Just why are you wearing the hiking shoes?
-惊喜吧 -什么 又来
- Surprise! - What, again?
每天早上整个一家子都要去登山
Every morning the whole family's gonna go hiking.
这样一星期下来
Then at the end of the week,
我们就都能爬到火山顶了
we all gonna make it to the top of the volcano.
每天早上是吧
Every morning, huh?
是啊 当时小卡一提
Yes. When Cam suggested it,
我就知道这主意你肯定喜欢
I knew you were gonna love it.
-原来是你的鬼主意啊 -生日快乐 杰
- Oh, so this was your idea? - Happy birthday, Jay.
谢谢啊 老兄
Ah, thanks, buddy. Ow.
小甜心好啊
Hi, sweetheart!
-我要去登山啦 -她在笑啊
- I'm going hiking! - She's smiling!
谢谢
Thank you.
看 老妈 我怀孕了
Look, Mom, I'm pregnant.
好的 不过你还是得吃晕海宁
Yeah. You still gotta take your Dramamine.
这儿谁会晕机吗
Oh, does somebody get a little motion sickness?
我能从头吐到尾
Yeah, I throw up all the time.
那你得赶紧吃点晕海宁
Oh, well, then Dramamine's the way to go.
你这是想干什么啊
What the hell are you doing?
现在不能让她睡着
Oh, I'm just trying to keep her awake
这样上了飞机她就能睡着了
so she'll sleep on the plane.
没人会喜欢乘飞机碰上个大哭的婴儿
Nobody likes a crying baby on a flight.
烦人得很
It's-It's very stressful.
去年我从纽约飞回来的时候
Uh, last year I flew back from New York...
旁边就有个婴儿吵了一整路
next to a baby who was very upset the entire flight,
备受煎熬啊
and it was hell.
我不是跟你一班飞机嘛 我怎么不记得...
I was on that flight with you, and I don't recall-
我知道了 你指的是我
Oh, I get it. You're talking about me.
真好笑哦
That's very funny.
我们没能买到《舞出我天地》的票
Yeah, we couldn't get tickets to Billy Elliot.
他就只想能够跳上舞 说的是我
All he wanted to do was dance, and that's my story.
叨逼叨了五个小时
Five hours of this.
"我就想能跳上芭蕾"
I just want to dance at the ballet!
晕海宁 上次坐飞机之前我吃点这个就好了
Dramamine. Oh, I wish I had that the last time I flew.
跟你说那飞机可是 忽上忽下 忽左忽右
Tell you, the plane was rocking up and down, back and forth.
当时我真以为机翼给折断了呢
I thought the wings were gonna snap off, honestly.
你自己拆吧 用牙咬
you do it yourself. Use your teeth.
这是最快的路线吗 怎么不上高速
I-Is this the best way to go? What about the freeway?
放轻松 交给我了
Relax, punkin. I got this.
关键在于要熟悉路线
It's all about knowing the route.
你面前的可是靠蹬三轮车
You're talking to a guy who made his way
挣学费念完大学的
through college by driving a pedicab.
-知道三轮车是什么吗 -知道知道
- You know what one of those is? - Yes. Yes.
就是刚刚超过我们的那辆
I just saw one pass us.
-抢答 《邪恶女人》是谁唱的 -啥
- Quick- Who sang "Evil Woman"? - What?
ELO组合[音同Hello]
ELO!
菲尔 你死哪去了
Phil, where the hell are you?
我看看 靠 转弯口我给错过了
Uh, let's see. Oh, shoot! I just missed my turn.
你这会儿理应呆在这陪着我
You're supposed to be here with me.
告诉过你的 越是接近起飞
I told you, I get more and more freaked out
我就会变得越抓狂
as we get closer to the flight.
是的 不过米奇...
Well, I know, but Mitch- Okay, you know what?
我本来还指望你能陪陪我 真是谢谢你了
I was counting on you to be here, so thanks a lot.
她紧张得要疯了
She's pretty tightly wound.
有些人就是天性使然
Some people are just built that way.
你敢开得再慢一点吗
Honestly, could you drive any slower?
猜猜世界最大的风力发电机在哪里
Guess where the world's largest wind generator is.
是不是我身后这个
Is it right behind me?
错 在瓦胡岛上[夏威夷群岛之主岛]
Nope. It's on the island of Oahu.
我考虑把它加进我的夏威夷之歌里
I'm thinking about using it in my song about Hawaii.
什么歌
What song?
-老妈没告诉你吗 -惊喜
- Didn't Mom tell you? - Surprise!
一大家子准备给你的生日弄个汇演助兴
The whole family's putting on a show for you for your birthday.
每个人都要上台表演 菲尔都把木偶拿来了
Everybody's performing. Even Phil brought his dummy.
是不是很棒啊
Isn't that great?
-杰 -抱歉
- Jay? - Oh, I'm sorry.
我只是在想如果我一不小心
I was just thinking how tragic it would be
掉进火山可就悲剧了
if I fell into that volcano.
宝贝 别说胡话
Ay, papi, don't say that.
待会儿睡 宝贝 待会儿睡
Not yet, sweetie. Not yet.
看 真是完美无缺
See? He's perfect.
他连买咖啡都不加巧克力的
Look at him getting coffee and not putting chocolate in it.
真是成熟
He's so mature.
那迪兰怎么办
What about Dylan?
迪兰可比不上他
Dylan's no that guy.
海莉 赶紧的
Haley! Come on!
还有两分钟就要出发了 起床
We're leaving in two minutes! Get up!
-我的天啊 -不会吧 已经是第二天了
- Oh, my God! - Oh, no. Is it tomorrow?
迪兰 你在这儿干嘛
Dylan! What are you doing here?
我是想走的 但是见你入睡
I was gonna go, but then you fell asleep,
想到你要离开一个星期
and since you're leaving for a week,
我就寻思着能多看几眼就多看几眼
I want to stare at you as long as I could.
赶紧走吧 要不然我爸妈会以为我们做过了
You have to go. My parents are gonna think we did it.
我还想呢
As if.
赶快出去 千万别让别人发现
Get out of the house and make sure that nobody sees you.
我会想你的
I'II miss you.
你这一走 我就像一个
When you're gone, it's like I'm
困在寂寞小岛上的囚犯
this prisoner trapped in a cell of loneliness.
说得真好 不过你真得走了
That's beautiful, but you have to go.
好的
Okay.
我讨厌这种感觉 特讨厌
I hate this feeling. I hate it.
越是快上飞机这感觉就会越强烈
And it's just gonna get worse and worse until the flight. - Hey!
没事的啦
It's gonna be fine.
有菲尔大叔在呢
Uncle Phil's here.
-好样的伙计 第一个准备好的 -谢谢
- Great job, buddy! First one ready. - Thanks.
海莉 艾丽克斯 要走了
Haley and Alex, let's go! Coming.
上帝保佑
Bless you.
-来了 -好的快跟上 姑娘们
- Coming. - All right. Come on, girls.
好的
Okay.
-练兵千日 用兵一时 -就来 就来
- This is why we practice. - Come on through. Come through.
-十五秒的时间 准备好了吗 -好了
- Fifteen seconds. Are we ready? - Yes.
动起来吧
It's go time.
直奔小车 欲速则不达 慢慢来
Straight to the car. Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast.
欲速则不达 慢慢来 直接走
Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast. Straight through.
-太棒了 -赶紧走 赶紧走
- Very nice! - All right. Let's go. Let's go.
-好像还多余几秒钟呢 -不多
- I think we got an extra couple of seconds. - No,
-没有 -老爸 赶紧的
- we don't. - Dad, come on!
-我去 -怎么了
- Oh, no! - What?
我的钥匙
My keys!
撑住啊 宝贝 别睡着
Stay awake, sweetie. Stay awake.
瞧 噢不
Whee! Oh, no.
房产经纪人培训就是用来对付这个的
This is where your Realtor training comes in handy.
看着像是标准的波特森D型顶锁
Looks like a standard Porter and Sons D-Model top lock.
快速刷一下应该就能打开
One quick swipe oughta pop it.
上去吧
All aboard.
-好的 -走起
- Okay. - There we go.
小心一点
Nice and easy.
-你夹痛我了 夹痛我了 -不好意思
- Yeah, you're pinching. You're pinching. - I'm sorry.
经手千万房屋 习得百般技艺
If you show enough houses, you learn all the tricks.
每个房产经纪人可都是深藏不露的大师
Every Realtor is just a ninja in a blazer.
一般的小毛贼入室行窃
The average burglar breaks in
会留下各种蛛丝马迹
and leaves clues everywhere,
我可不会
but not me.
哥来无影 去无踪
I'm completely clueless.
我这么重你还吃得消吗
You're sure I'm not too heavy?
怎么会 我打彩弹枪穿的护具都比你重
Please, you weigh less than my paintball gear.
-好了 -好嘞 进来了
- Okay. Yup. - There we go. We are in.
下来吧 压到脖子了
Off-load. On we go. Squeezing.
-缓一会儿 -你没事吧
- I'm going for a ride. - You all right?
没事 没事
Yup. I'm good. I'm good.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
提防着下次再有人想破窗而入
Just making it a little tougher on the next guy.
聪明人总是先别人一步 我靠...
You got to get up pretty early- Son of a-
-你没事吧 -我没事
- Are you all right? - Yes, I am.
差点被你们家的救火车搞死
Just, uh, almost killed myself on your fire truck.
那不是我们家的 是贾斯珀的
That's not ours. That's Jasper's.
你们认识贾斯珀
You know Jasper?
他爸妈从我这买过一栋房子
I sold a house to his parents.
你们是怎么约到他来家里玩的
How did you ever get a playdate with him?
赶紧走吧 拜托
Let's go! Please, can- yeah. Okay.
你瞅瞅 他在素描哎
Look at him. He's sketching.
就像泰坦尼克号里的莱昂纳多一样
He's like Leonardo DiCaprio in Titanic.
我打赌他一定是艺术院校的
I bet he goes to art school.
你说他是不是在画我俩呢
Do you think he's sketching us?
是啊 我"俩"
Yeah. "Us."
于5点30分飞波士顿的航班现在开始登机
Check-in for the 5:30 flight to Boston may board at this time.
对上眼了
And contact.
是迪兰
It's Dylan.
"我被困住了" 哎呦喂 真能折腾
"I'm trapped." Yeah, yeah, yeah. What a drama queen.
我们要去"浣赏"鲸鱼
We will go whale washing,
探索热带雨林
explore the tropical forest,
回归大自然
get back into the nature.
听起来不错啊
That sounds fun. Mm-hmm.
-谢谢 -不谢
- Thanks. - Thank you.
请注意
Your attention, please.
请曼尼·迪尔加多到22A登机口
Will Manny Delgado please report to Gate 22-A?
曼尼·迪尔加多到22A登机口
Manny Delgado to Gate 22-A.
快看 外公 晕海宁起作用了
Check it out, Grandpa. The Dramamine's working.
我一点都不晕
I'm not dizzy.
小心饮料 小鬼
Yeah. Oh, watch the drink, kid.
哦 我的小说
Ooh! Ooh, my Ludlums!
-对不起 外公 -没事 别紧张
- I'm sorry, Grandpa. - All right. Relax, relax.
可能没什么大碍
We might be okay here.
上天待我不公 上天待我不公
It's not fair. It's not fair.
抱歉女士 他是曼尼·迪尔加多吗
Excuse me, ma'am. Is this Manny Delgado?
-是的 -你儿子的名字在禁飞名单里
- Yes. - Your son's name is on a no-fly list.
拜托 安检那会儿就跟我们核实过了
Ay, please, we've been through this at the check-in.
他不是名单里的那个曼尼·迪尔加多
He's not the same Manny Delgado.
我就是个想重现旅行格调的男孩
I'm just a boy trying to bring style back to travel.
-我们只想核实几个问题 -这是个误会
- We just have a few questions to ask. - No, this is a mistake.
-我老公人呢 杰 -这边请 女士
- Where is my husband? Wait. Jay! - Step this way, ma'am.
女士 请这边走
Ma'am, step this way, please.
-孩子 这边走 -杰 别推我 杰
- Son, step this way. - Jay! No pushing. Jay!
给我双份的量吧 我一家老小一起旅行
You make it a double? I'm traveling with my family.
没问题
No problem.
跟个男人一起生活肯定简单多了吧
Must be a lot easier just living with a guy.
我要是同性恋 生活肯定简单得多
Yeah, life would be simpler if I was gay.
你能不能挤进快车道啊[适应这种生活]
Do you think you could get in the fast lane?
-我当然能适应了 -我指的是路
- Oh, I could totally get in the fast lane. - I mean the road.
我来了条短信 说的什么
Oh, I'm getting a text. What does it say?
哦没啥事 是报警器公司
Um- Oh, G- Well, it's nothing. It's the alarm company.
-说你家有人闯入 -什么
- It says your house was broken into. - What?
没啥事 他们会处理的 你开你的
It's nothing. They'll take care of it. Just drive!
到底怎么了
What happened?
来玩个有趣的机场游戏
Okay, fun airport game.
随便挑一个旅客 虚构他们的整个人生
You pick out a traveler, you come up with their entire story.
比如这个男人 他叫亨利
Okay. This guy, his name's Henry.
他准备去凤凰城看他的祖母
He's on his way to Phoenix to visit his grandmother,
祖母名叫...
whose name is, uh-
放弃
Oh! Pass.
-太难了 你来 -好的
- Too hard. Your turn. - Okay. Fine.
我看见一个女人 她惊恐万分
I see a woman, uh, wracked with fear,
还被她老公给抛弃了
whose husband has abandoned her.
-哪里 说谁呢 -我
- Where? Where? Who is she? - Me.
我跟菲尔说的清清楚楚要他在这陪着我
I made it perfectly clear to Phil that I needed him here.
我也一样 米奇尔也在生我的气
Oh. It's going around. Mitchell's mad at me too.
他觉得就是因为早上我没帮他整理行李
He thinks because I didn't help him pack this morning,
才让他忘带钱包
he forgot his wallet.
对不起 我有一点烦躁
I'm-I'm sorry. I'm sorry to be snippy.
我一直在生小卡的气
It's just... I'm a little upset with Cam.
早上打包要他的帮忙 结果他却让我失望了
I needed his help this morning, and he let me down.
我印象中的小卡不是这样的啊
That doesn't sound like him.
你请他帮忙他却不闻不问
You asked him to do something and he didn't do it?
没见他开口说啊 他就在那一直说
But he never asked! I mean, all he said was,
"莉莉的东西要装好
"Lily's bag needs to be packed
报纸要暂停寄送"
and the newspaper needs to be canceled."
我听着就像是在向你求助啊
That sounds to me like he was asking for help.
我听着你简直就是想让他能通灵啊
Sounds to me like you expected him to read your mind.
-当我有超能力啊 -不是说让你有超能力
- What am I, a psychic? - No! It's not about reading minds.
是说要了解另一半的需要
It's about knowing what your partner needs.
不如这样 直接说"帮我个忙"
Here's an idea: Just say "Help me."
"我"都可以省了 "帮个忙"就好
You don't even have to say "Me," Just "Help."
这样他就明白你到底要什么了
Then he'll know exactly what you want.
你也不至于憋一肚子气
You won't have to get all mad.
倒没憋一肚子气 只是...
I'm not mad. It's just-
你总是希望能和一个人心有灵犀
You wanna believe you're on the same wavelength as someone,
可到头来
and then it's just-
发现其实没那么默契时 总有点沮丧
it's a little disheartening when you find out you're not.
就这样
That's all.
最难受的是我明明愿意为他付出所有
What's frustrating is I would do anything for Mitchell,
可他却看不出来 说实话我有点伤心
and-and frankly, it's a little hurtful that he doesn't know that.
机场可真吵杂啊
So, airports, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
你在画什么呢
Are you drawing something there?
恩 画得一般般啦
Yeah. It's no good.
内心纠结的艺术家 妙极了
Tortured artist. Classic.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
-是个机器人 -可不是嘛
- It's a robot. - Oh, yeah. Sure is.
-背后那个是什么 -一只恐龙
- What's behind him? - A dinosaur.
学校的作业 让我们画连环画
It's for school. We're supposed to make a comic strip.
我们也要做哎 就八年级那会儿...
We had to do that too, back in the eighth-
他才14岁
He was 14 years old.
闭嘴
Shut up.
"他是我的灵魂伴侣"
"He's my soul mate."
我...
I d-
以下是最后一遍登机通告...
This is the final boarding announcement for-
你在喝什么
What you drinking?
爸 好啊
Dad. Hey.
大部分是汤力水 要谢谢这位大哥
Mostly tonic actually, thanks to my new sponsor here.
我一想到坐飞机就心里发憷
I'm a little jittery about flying.
你在说什么呢 你乘过很多次飞机了啊
What are you talking about? You fly all the time.
是啊 也就这几年开始的
Yeah, I know. This started just in the last couple years.
我觉得 之所以会紧张
I think I'm just- I'm nervous
可能是因为现在有很多东西放不下吧
'cause I've got so much to lose now, you know?
你是怎么回事
What about you?
来喘口气 不用想着度假的事
I'm taking a break from my vacation.
度假可还没开始呢
We haven't even started yet.
我是觉得吧 真到那个时候我就没个清静了
Well, I gotta figure, I might not have a lot of time for myself,
一会儿烤猪宴 一会儿爬山 一会儿表演
you know, what with the luaus, the hiking, the talent shows.
我们一大家陪你来 你不开心吗
Are you not happy that we're coming with you?
只是跟我的初衷有些不一样
It's just not what I expected.
不过老爸 我们这样你难道不感动吗
But, Dad, doesn't it feel good to know...
一家人都甘愿抛下一切来陪你
that your whole family is willing to drop everything to be with you,
还必须坐那铁棺材横跨大洋
to fly across the ocean in a steel coffin?
你那杯剩下的也给我吧
I'm gonna finish that.
跟你们无关 我爱全家
It's not you guys. I love the family.
我是感觉歌洛莉亚在想方设法地
It just kinda feels like Gloria's going out of her way...
避免跟我单独相处
not to spend time with me.
你不是认真的吧
You don't believe that, do you?
拜托 老爸
Oh, come on, Dad!
你真是太傻太可爱了
That is so crazy and so adorable.
那女人是爱你的
That woman loves you.
我又没说我不招人爱
Well, I didn't say I wasn't lovable.
不是每个做老婆的都愿意花钱
It's not every wife that would spend the money
让全家去夏威夷旅游的
to fly a family to Hawaii.
好吧 你们以为歌洛莉亚的钱哪里来的啊
Okay. Where does everybody think Gloria's money comes from?
你之前在日本从事什么活动
So, what kind of business did you have in Japan?
我压根就没去过日本
I've never been to Japan.
你在2003年的11月
You didn't go to Osaka
有没有去大阪参加电子贸易展
November 2003 to attend an electronics trade show?
那时我才4岁
I was four.
够了 你怎么不去门口随便抓个人来盘问
Enough. Why don't you question the other people on the gate, huh?
看到那个拄着拐杖的老妇人了吗
Did you see the old lady with the cane?
那拐杖里说不定藏了个
What if she has a ceramic knife
金属探测器查不出来的陶瓷刀呢
in there that can go through the metal detector?
你却在这里把时间浪费在骚扰小孩子上
And yet you waste your time harassing a little kid.
女士 你似乎非常了解
Ma'am, you seem to know an awful lot about
如何偷带违禁品上飞机啊
sneaking contraband on to a plane.
是啊 姐可是哥伦比亚人
Yeah, I'm Colombian.
那你有没有去过日本呢
Have you ever been to Japan?
我想先打一通电话
I would like to make a phone call.
女士们先生们 飞往茂伊岛的航班
Ladies and gentlemen, preboarding for our flight to Maui...
马上开始办理登机
will begin in the next few minutes.
-卢克 快别转了 -对不起
- Luke, please stop spinning. - Sorry.
能不能让机场也别再转了
Now make the airport stop spinning.
我们做到啦 克莱尔
We made it! Claire!
谢天谢地 你终于来了
Oh, my God. Thank God you're here.
亲爱的
Oh, honey!
-真是对不起 -都是我不好
- I am so sorry. - It was my fault.
-不是你的错 -我应该想到你要什么的
- It wasn't your fault. - I should have known what you wanted.
-你是不是喝高了 -有点吧
- Are you drunk? - Kinda.
有次我去墨西哥的坎昆玩了一周
And once I spent a week in Cancún,
要我说 远远没有传说得那么好玩
which, by the way, did not live up to the hype.
来个人跟我解释一下这是怎么回事
Can somebody tell me what the hell is going on?
我们就快问完了 先生
We're almost done here, sir.
-你和你的儿子计划一同旅行是吗 -是的
- So you and your son are traveling together? - Yes.
那为什么你们离开茂伊岛的时间不同
Then why are you departing Maui on different dates?
因为他要和一大家子先回来
Well, because he's traveling back home with his family.
-什么 -惊喜
- What? - Surprise!
他们只在那呆6天
They're only staying for six days.
-剩下来的时间只属于我们俩 -真的吗
- The rest of the time it's only you and me. - Really?
嗯呀 我就想跟我老公单独待一会儿
Mm-hmm. I wanted to spend some time alone with my husband-
在泳池边上喝点鸡尾酒啊 睡睡懒觉
drink cocktails by the pool, sleep in.
我现在已经爱你到无以复加了
I could not love you any more than I do right now.
我还找到了一个裸体沙滩
I also found a topless beach.
那我只能更爱你了
I was wrong.
杰克逊先生 旅途愉快
Mr. Jackson, have a great flight.
请走左边 真漂亮
It's to the left. Oh, gorgeous!
-谢谢 是复古衫 -他是在说莉莉吧
- Oh, thank you. It's vintage. - Think he meant Lily.
你又说不准
You don't know that.
五点钟方向有个适合你的帅哥哦
Hey, there's another hottie for you at 5:00.
他想必应该是个艺术家
I think he's an artist.
是"观赏"鲸鱼
It's whale "Watching."
-"浣赏"鲸鱼 -"观赏"
- Whale washing. - Watching.
-"浣赏" -差不多了
- Washing. - That's close enough.
旅途愉快 先生
Have a good flight, sir.
快 扮个僵尸给人看看
Quick, do your zombie impression.
-她不是喝醉了吧 -没有没有
- She hasn't been drinking, has she? - Oh, no, no, no.
她在搞笑呢 再来一个"僵尸抱"
She's- She's hilarious. Okay, let's do bride of Frankenstein.
真是太 太逼真了
It's so, so good.